welcome to another video editing
欢迎使用另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive in this video we're going to be
Kdenlive在这段视频中我们将成为
creating a picture slideshow so we don't
创建一个图片幻灯片 这样我们就不会
have to just use kdenlive for video
我只能使用kdenlive观看视频
editing we can also bring in pictures
编辑时 我们还可以添加图片
and we can apply the same effects that
我们可以应用相同的效果
we've been learning about then different
我们一直在学习不同的东西
options to those pictures we can add
我们可以添加这些图片的选项
music to be playing while the pictures
在播放图片的同时播放音乐
are being displayed so I'm just going to
都在展示 所以我要
go to a few different places on my
去我的几个不同的地方
computer where I have some pictures I'll
我有几张照片的电脑 我会
just left-click and drag those into my
只需左键单击并将它们拖到我的
project bin over here and then we see we
项目垃圾箱在这里 然后我们看到我们
can look at these different pictures and
可以看到这些不同的图片
see which ones we want to add maybe I
看看我们想要添加哪些 也许我
want to add this picture first
我想先添加此图片
so I'll left-click and drag it down to
因此 我将左键单击并将其拖到
this video one track and then for the
这个视频只有一首曲目 然后
next picture I'll do this one of the guy
下一张照片我要拍这张照片
falling and for the last picture I'll do
坠落 为了最后一张照片 我会做
the one with the little boy so we drag
有个小男孩的那个 所以我们拖着
and put them all in here and now we have
把它们都放在这里 现在我们有了
these different pictures we can see with
这些我们可以看到的不同的图片
your play by default these are gonna be
默认情况下 您的游戏将是
five seconds long each I'll just resize
每个5秒长 我要调整大小
the timeline here yeah so by default
这里的时间线是的 所以默认情况下
they're each five seconds long and that
他们每个人都有5秒长 而且
might be a little bit long for me like
对我来说可能有点长 就像
if we click play we can see it shows the
如果我们点击播放 我们可以看到它显示了
picture for quite a while then it
画了好一阵子 然后它
switches right to the next picture but
向右切换到下一张图片 但
we can resize them we can go down we can
我们可以调整它们的大小 我们可以降低它们的尺寸
actually just double click on the clip
实际上只需双击剪辑即可
and it says duration five five seconds
上面写着持续5秒5秒
so we can change this and type in 4 or
因此我们可以更改此选项并键入4或
even 3 and hit OK and it'll look length
即使是3 然后点击OK 它看起来就像是长度
lower the length of that to 3 so we can
把它的长度降低到3 这样我们就可以
go to each of these clips and do that if
转到这些剪辑中的每一个并在以下情况下执行此操作
we want go 3 enter double click give it
我们要Go 3 Enter 双击给它
a three and then it enter or hit the
一个三 然后它进入或击中
okay button and now there are three
好的 按钮 现在有三个
seconds long each we can drag them so
几秒钟的时间 我们可以把它们拖到
they're close together otherwise we get
他们靠得很近 否则我们会
this black if we didn't drag it close to
如果我们不把它拉近的话这个黑色
each other we'd get a black gap in
我们会在对方身上留下黑色的缝隙
between the pictures so we drag them so
所以我们把它们拖到
that they just goes from one picture to
他们只是从一张照片转到
the next and then when we play it just
下一次 然后当我们播放的时候
goes and transitions just cuts over to
去和过渡只是切换到
the next picture another way that you
下一张照片是你用另一种方式
can change the length of how long it's
可以改变它的长度
being displayed for is by hovering to
通过将鼠标悬停到
the end of the video clip or the
视频剪辑的结尾或
beginning of the picture clip of
的图片剪辑的开头
whatever it is and then you can drag it
不管它是什么 然后你就可以拖它了
out and make it longer or
让它变得更长 或者
shorter so whatever one's selected is
更短 所以无论选择什么 都是
who the ones will do so we'll make that
谁会做 所以我们会做的
always a little bit shorter and that
总是短一点 那就是
looks pretty good
看起来挺不错的
so now our total video project is like
所以现在我们的整个视频项目就像
what seven or eight seconds long or not
什么七八秒长？
even about five seconds long so now
即使只有五秒长 现在也是如此
we'll play all these clips within a
我们将在一个
period of five seconds just very quickly
5秒的时间 非常快
playing through a couple different
玩了几个不同的游戏
pictures yeah that's that's the basic
图片 是的 这是最基本的
that's basically it we could edit this
基本上就是这样 我们可以编辑这个
picture we see it we have black bars on
想象我们看到了它 我们戴着黑条
the right and left side of this picture
这张图片的左边和右边
so we could edit this picture in like
这样我们就可以像这样编辑这张照片
Photoshop or to make sure that it
Photoshop或确保它
fits a 1920 by 1080 make sure it fits
1920年到1080年的合身 确保合身
like a widescreen view same with these
就像宽屏视图和这些一样
ones these ones are actually even have a
这些人实际上甚至有一个
little bit of bars on the side of them
在它们的边上有一些小栏杆
because it's not exactly a full
因为这并不完全是一个完整的
widescreen picture but we can also edit
宽屏图片 但我们也可以编辑
it here in kdenlive if we'd rather do
如果我们更愿意在Kdenlive这里做
that so I'll show you like this one for
所以我会给你展示一下这个
example we just go to crop and transform
例如 我们只需进行裁剪和变换
and then we do this edge crop so I'll
然后我们做这个边缘裁剪 所以我将
left click and drag it over top of the
左键单击并将其拖到顶部
picture and if we get these options over
如果我们通过这些选项
here in properties come up if these
在这里 如果这些属性出现
don't come up for you sometimes they're
有时候他们不会为你而来
they're hiding within here it's a
他们藏在这里 这是一个
separate tab so we've got effects
分开制表符 这样我们就有了效果
transitions and properties but I have
转换和属性 但我有
mine configured so that it's over here
我的配置好了 所以它在这里
and again if you couldn't find the
再说一次 如果你找不到
effects that's where they were to you
这就是它们对你的影响
were about maybe looking at transitions
可能是在考虑过渡
and not effects so I always look there's
而不是效果 所以我总是看着
tabs under all these different things
所有这些不同内容下的选项卡
there's always tabs that can confuse you
总有一些标签会让你感到困惑
if you know if you're not on the right
如果你知道如果你不在右边
tab anyway so right now we have this
不管怎么说 现在我们有这个
clip selected properties we can just
剪裁选定的属性 我们只需
crop the sides so we want to crop the
裁剪侧面 这样我们就可以裁剪
the right-hand side and the left-hand
右手边和左手边
side so we should go over to right and
所以我们应该向右转
we crop in a little bit and what that's
我们突然插话 这是什么？
doing is just kind of cutting in oh I'm
这样做只是一种插手 哦 我
just I'm kidding actually we didn't want
我只是在开玩笑实际上我们不想
to do that because to get rid of this
这样做是因为要摆脱这个
black box we actually need to crop the
我们实际上需要裁剪黑匣子
bottom and top so and I mean I don't
所以我的意思是我不想
want to crop the top any because I'll
想剪掉顶端吗 因为我会
cut it into the face
切开它的脸
so I'm going to crop the bottom so by
所以我要修剪底部 这样到
cutting out the bottom of the picture it
把这幅画的底部剪掉
actually gets rid of these black lines
实际上去掉了这些黑线
because it's making our picture more of
因为这让我们的照片更像
the shape we want it to be does that
我们想要的形状就是这样的
make sense so we cut out a bunch of the
有道理 所以我们剪掉了一堆
bottom and then it just kind of made
底部 然后它就像是
this picture fill our full screen
这幅画占满了我们的整个屏幕
a better example might be this one of
一个更好的例子可能是
the little boy so let's come over here
这个小男孩 我们到这边来吧
and this one I'll do a edge crop we drag
而这一次 我将做一个边缘裁剪 我们拖着
this over and now this one we want we
这一切都结束了 现在我们想要的是我们
this one we do want to crop to the left
这一张我们确实想剪到左边
and the right don't we know this is the
而右翼我们不知道这是
same thing we want to crop the top and
和我们想要裁剪顶部和
the bottom because we want to cut off
底部是因为我们想切断
this much of the top and cut off of this
顶端的这一大部分和切断的这一部分
much of the bottom so that all we're
大部分的底部 所以我们都是
viewing is just in on the face so if we
观看只是在脸上 所以如果我们
start cutting it right here that's
从这里开始剪 这是
pretty good that's about as far in and
很好 这大约是在和
we want to be about that far away from
我们想要离那个地方那么远
the chin and then we go to the top and
下巴 然后我们到顶端
drop in a little bit more to and then we
再来一趟 然后我们
get a nice shot just like this that's
拍得很好 就像这样
pretty cool huh this is easier to deal
很酷吧 这更容易处理
again and like or Photoshop but you
一次又一次的喜欢或Photoshop但你
can I just want to show that you can do
我能不能只想证明你有能力
it using this yeah this edge crop so now
它使用这个 对 这个边缘裁剪 所以现在
we see we have a nice picture we didn't
我们看到我们有一张我们没有的好照片
do the one of the following so we still
执行以下操作之一 以便我们仍然
have the black bars on the side but
把黑条放在一边 但是
that's okay and then we have a nice this
没关系 然后我们有一个很好的这个
one looks a lot better than it did
其中一款看起来比以前好多了
before see before if we turn off this
在此之前 请看我们是否将其关闭
effect it was so far out and you
效果是太远了 而你
couldn't really see now we can see a lot
我真的看不到现在我们可以看到很多
more detail and just fills the whole
更多细节 恰好填满了整个
screen which looks a lot better yeah
屏幕看起来好多了是的
that's all I want to do in this video oh
这就是我在这段视频中想要做的一切哦
let's add music real quick so just for
让我们很快地添加音乐 只是为了
fun we can go to our downloads I should
有趣的是 我们可以去我们的下载我应该
get some more music I still have just
再弄点音乐来 我还有
this one kind of video this clip so
这一种视频这个剪辑所以
we'll drag it down to our audio and then
我们会把它拖到我们的音频上 然后
we can do the same thing with the audio
我们可以对音频做同样的事情
to resize it hover to the end just
要调整它的大小 只需将鼠标悬停到最后
left-click and drag all the way now our
左键单击并一直拖动 现在我们的
audio is just the same length as our
音频的长度与我们的
video project which is a picture
视频项目 这是一张图片
slideshow so we'll play this see it
幻灯片放映 我们将播放这个 请看
looks like cool so that's it in the next
看起来很酷 所以这就是下一个
video I'm gonna keep this all up in the
视频我会把这一切都保留在
next video we'll be looking at using
下一个视频我们将使用
different transitions to create like a
不同的过渡以创建类似于
transition effect between the pictures
画面之间的过渡效果
and sit adjust I could cut over like
坐着调整 我可以像这样切开
this will transition hopefully you found
希望这会过渡到你发现的
this video informative go ahead and like
这段视频内容丰富 请继续点赞
and subscribe if you had and yeah leave
如果你有的话 请订阅 然后离开
comments below tell me what kind of
下面的评论告诉我是什么样的
videos you'd like me to make in the
你想让我在
future super curious to know I'll catch
未来超级好奇 想知道我会追上
on the next video
在下一个视频中